<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biostatistics on Monash Bioinformatics Platform</title>
    <link>/tags/biostatistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in biostatistics on Monash Bioinformatics Platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 20:53:28 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/biostatistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Borrowing strength in numbers: some ideas for bulk and single-cell RNA-seq analysis</title>
      <link>/posts/davis-mccarthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 20:53:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/davis-mccarthy/</guid>
      <description>High-throughput data generation technologies are driving discovery in biomedical science</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singscore for gene-set scoring in cancer research</title>
      <link>/posts/joseph-cursons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 20:49:20 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/joseph-cursons/</guid>
      <description>The recent decade has seen a massive growth in the availability of large transcriptomic data sets for cell line collections (e.g. the Cancer Cell Line Encyclopedia; CCLE), and patient tumour samples with matched clinical information (e.g. The Cancer Genome Atlas; TCGA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration of miR-196 and retinoic acid signaling in limb development</title>
      <link>/posts/jan-schroeder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 20:46:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/jan-schroeder/</guid>
      <description>Integration of miR-196 and retinoic acid signaling in limb development and patterning Retinoic acid signaling can be inhibited with a drug treatment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beggars at a banquet: stop only thinking about significance and start thinking about measurement accuracy with topconfects</title>
      <link>/posts/paul-harrison/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 20:40:31 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/paul-harrison/</guid>
      <description>Paul Harrison
Monash Bioinformatics Platform
RNA System laboratory
Abstract In this talk I will describe ranking and selecting differentially expressed genes based on confidence bounds on the log fold change, while still properly adjusting for multiple-testing, using my Bioconductor package &amp;ldquo;topconfects&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>